foundersfcu.com 2019-05-25

# FACTS

                                                                                                                    Rev 12/2018
                      WHAT DOES FOUNDERS FEDERAL CREDIT UNION
FACTS                 DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
                      Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives
Why?                  consumers the right to limit some, but not all, sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you
                      how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to
                      understand what we do.
                      The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you
 What?                have with us. This information can include:
                      • Social Security number and income.
                      • Account balances and payment history.
                      • Credit history and credit scores.
                      When you are no longer our member, we continue to share your information as described in this
                      notice.
                      All financial companies need to share members’ personal information to run their everyday
 How?                 business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their members’
                      personal information; the reasons Founders Federal Credit Union chooses to share; and whether
                      you can limit this sharing.
                                                               Does Founders Federal
Reasons we can share your personal information                                                Can you limit this sharing?
                                                                Credit Union share?
For our everyday business purposes—
such as to process your transactions, maintain
                                                                         Yes                               No
your account(s), respond to court orders and legal
investigations, or report to credit bureaus
For our marketing purposes—
                                                                         Yes                               No
to offer our products and services to you
For joint marketing with other financial companies                        No                        We don’t share
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes—
                                                                          No                        We don’t share
information about your transactions and experiences
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes—
                                                                          No                        We don’t share
information about your creditworthiness
For our affiliates to market to you                                      Yes                               Yes
For our nonaffiliates to market to you                                    No                        We don’t share
                      • Mail the form below.
 To limit             • Call 1-800-845-1614.
 our sharing          Please note:
                      If you are a new member, we can begin sharing your information 30 days from the date we sent
                      this notice. When you are no longer our member, we continue to share your information as
                      described in this notice.
                      However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.
 Questions?           Call 1-800-845-1614.
 Mail-in Form (You are not required to complete this form if you have done so in the past.)
                      Do not allow your affiliates to use my personal information to market to me.
                     Name                                                                            Mail to:
                                                                                                     Founders Federal
                     Address
                                                                                                     Credit Union
                                                                                                     Attn: Compliance
                     City, State, Zip                                                                Officer
                                                                                                     737 Plantation Road
                     Account
                     Number                                                                          Lancaster, SC
                                                                                                     29720

   What we do
   How does Founders Federal Credit                           To protect your personal information from unauthorized access
   Union protect my personal information?                     and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law.
                                                              These measures include computer safeguards and secured files
                                                              and buildings.
   How does Founders Federal Credit                           We collect your personal information, for example, when you
   Union collect my personal information?                     • open an account or deposit money
                                                              • pay your bills or apply for a loan
                                                              • use your credit or debit card
                                                              We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit
                                                              bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.
    Why can’t I limit all sharing?                            Federal law gives you the right to limit only
                                                              • sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes—information about
                                                                 your creditworthiness
                                                              • affiliates from using your information to market to you
                                                              • sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you
                                                              State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to
                                                              limit sharing.
    What happens when I limit sharing                         Your choices will apply to everyone on your account.
    for an account I hold jointly with
    someone else?
   Definitions
    Affiliates                                                Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                                              financial and nonfinancial companies.
                                                              • Our affiliate includes Founders Financial Group, LLC, doing business
                                                                 as Founders Insurance Services which provides insurance services.
    Nonaffiliates                                             Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be
                                                              financial and nonfinancial companies.
                                                              • Founders Federal Credit Union does not share with nonaffiliates so
                                                                 they can market to you.
   Joint marketing                                            A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that
                                                              together market financial products or services to you.
                                                              • Founders Federal Credit Union does not jointly market.
   Other Important Information
   Notices and “Joint Relationships.” Except where expressly required by applicable law, we will provide all notices to the person
   (member) listed first on any application, agreement or other relevant document with us. The notice will be mailed to the address
   noted for said person on the application, agreement or other document. If this person (member) has agreed to receive notices and
   disclosures electronically, then we can send all such notices and notifications, to the e-mail or Internet address provided by said
   person; or we shall post or otherwise give notice by posting a notice, providing a link or using such other electronic methods
   authorized under applicable laws and/or regulations. All joint owners, borrowers and guarantors agree to the receipt and sufficiency
   of any notice or notification sent according to this paragraph.
   Modification. The Credit Union reserves the right to modify, change or amend this Privacy Policy and Agreement at any time without
   notice other than as expressly required by applicable law.
   What members can do to help. Protect your account numbers, card numbers, PINs (personal identification numbers), and
   passwords. In particular, never keep your PIN with your debit card or credit card, as that makes you vulnerable in the event you
   lose your card or your card is stolen. Use caution in revealing account numbers, social security numbers, etc. to other persons. In
   particular, if a caller tells you he/she is calling you on behalf of the credit union and asks for your account number, you should beware.
   Legitimate credit union staff would already have access to that information. It’s important that the credit union has current information
   about how to reach you. If we detect potentially fraudulent use of your account, we will attempt to contact you immediately. If your
   address or phone number changes, please let us know.
   Protecting Children. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children and we do not knowingly market to children online.
   We recognize that protecting children’s identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents.
Form #4313
